# Haider Ali

+92-310-400-2205 · itshaider1998@gmail.com ·

https://github.com/haiddie · https://www.linkedin.com/in/haider-ali-23184a170/

318-C Nespak housing Society Phase 2, Canal Bank rd, Lahore

#### FRONTEND ENGINEER

"The best preparation for tomorrow is doing your best today." by H. Jackson Brown, Jr.

As a frontend engineer, I am committed to continuous learning and improvement, always aiming to expand my skill set and tackle new challenges. My goal is to contribute my diverse technical expertise and problem-solving abilities to dynamic projects that push the boundaries of web and mobile development.

### **KEY COMPETENCIES**

Web accessibility and performance optimization

Effective communication with both technical and non-technical team members

Time management and ability to work on multiple projects

### PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# Cinnova Technologies, LLC Senior Software Engineer

**December 2023 - Present** 

- Designed and implemented scalable and robust architectures for high-traffic web applications using microservices architecture and containerization.
- Developed end-to-end solutions, from front-end interfaces to back-end APIs, ensuring seamless integration and exceptional user experiences.
- Implemented performance tuning and optimization strategies, resulting in a 30% reduction in response times and improved application efficiency.

# Cinnova Technologies, LLC Software Engineer

September 2022 - December 2023

- Software Engineer
- Led the migration of legacy systems to a modern microservices architecture
- · Proactively researched emerging technologies and methodologies to drive continuous improvement

## SDSol Technologies

August 2021 - August 2022

## Associate Software Engineer

- Developed end-to-end solutions
- Developed new applications from scratch
- Improved the UI/UX of previous apps

## Codetreck

October 2019 - July 2021

# **Associate Software Engineer**

- Developed end-to-end solutions
- · Developed new applications from scratch
- · Researched and Designed the Structure for apps.
- Developed PWAs & Hybrid Apps

# Switch To Solutions MEAN/MERN STACK Internship

- · Learned new aspects of the technology
- Followed the mean stack course develop basic mean apps.
- Learned Code Improvement techniques

### **EDUCATION & CERTIFICATIONS**

# Bachelor's in Computer Science, Computer and Information Sciences,

Government College University, Lahore 2016 - 2020

## **Government College University, Lahore**

Ginyard International Co.

2014 - 2016

### **EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES**

- Football
- Basketball
- Table Tennis
- Photography
- Gaming
- Volleyball
- Foosball

## **DEVELOPMENT EXPERIENCES**

- MEAN Applications.
- · MERN Applications.
- PHP-based Custom API's in Laravel.
- Third Party Apis (Youtube, Twitter, Spotify & Musix Brainz)
- PostgreSQL & Lambda Functions.
- Firebase (FCM, PasswordLess Login, Push Notifications, RealTime DB & FireStore)
- · Social Logins.
- DeepLinking & InApp Purchase.
- Google Map Integration with live tracking.
- Google AdSense & Google Ads in app.
- Stripe Payment Integration
- Video & Audio Streaming & Downloads using MUX
- Hardware-Based Ionic Applications
- NGX DataTables, High Charts, Apex Charts, Google Charts
- Material UI Components
- Figma Inspired Functionalities (Drag & Drop, Custom Zoom)
- RealTime Chat Integration with video call
- Angular Dashboards
- React Dashboards
- PWAs
- Websites in React, Angular, NEXTJS.
- Custom Templates

## **SKILLS**

- Angular
- ReactJS
- Ionic
- Node Js
- React Js
- MongoDB
- PostGre SQL
- Next JS
- · AWS Lambda
- Typescript
- Javascript Firebase
- Capacitor
- Azure

Tappi Sep 2023 - Present

- · Associated with Cinnova Technologies, LLC
- Tappi is a Music Community Based Software. It inspires Music Artists to come forward with different ideas
  to connect the AI with the music. Using different Advanced tools we created the structure in NextJs and
  React.
- Our Future goals is to bring our software to the global platform.
- Skills: JavaScript · Next.js · TypeScript · PostgreSQL · React.js

<u>SportsWriters</u> Sep 2022 - Present

- Associated with Cinnova Technologies, LLC
- SportsWriters is a member-based sports community. Access to most of our content is for members only, however, it is free to sign up. If interested, members can create and submit content for publication.
   SportsWriters has set out to develop a better way to create and consume content that delivers engaging articles in a revolutionary format. These new Content Experiences are exclusive to SportsWriters. In addition to engaging original stories, SportsWriters provides indexed access to the latest news and stories written by the best writers covering the major sports leagues. SportsWriters curates and catalogs these articles, so you do not have to go searching for them. If that is not enough, for stats junkies, SportsWriters provides stats in a format different from other sports websites.
- Skills: Ionic · Scss · HTML · Node.js · PostgreSQL · Tailwind CSS · Angular 14

Gold Adder Oct 2020 - Jul 2021

- Associated with Codetreck
- GoldAdder is a powerful calculator, built as a FREE alternative to expensive graphing calculators needed for a modern math class. It was designed and built for students.
- Forgot your calculator at home? Forgot to charge? Lost it? Can't afford one? GoldAdder is available on all your devices, all the time. Download GoldAdder as an app to your computer, for use even without the internet.
- Customize your calculator with GoldAdder's built-in designer. Change color combinations and add images for a totally unique look. Go with your school colors one day. Use a selfie for your screen the next day. Create your own design or choose from GoldAdder's library of designs. GoldAdder is a powerful calculator, built as a FREE alternative to expensive graphing calculators needed for a modern math class. It was designed and built for students. Forgot your calculator at home? Forgot to charge? Lost it? Can't afford one? GoldAdder is available on all your devices, all the time. Download GoldAdder as an app to your computer, for use even without the internet. Customize your calculator with GoldAdder's built-in designer. Change color combinations and add images for a totally unique look. Go with your school colors one day. Use a selfie for your screen the next day. Create your own design or choose from GoldAdder's library of designs.
- Skills: HTML5 · Ionic Framework · Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) · TypeScript · NodeJs, MongoDB · Angular 14 .